A Finding Aid to the Eva Lee Gallery Records, 1921-1973, in the Archives of American Art AAA.evalee
Archives of American Art
- Financial Artist Files, 1921-1970; Series 3
  - Detroit Institute of Arts, 1944-1950 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Dove, Arthur, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Driggs, Elsie, 1931-1944 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Essinger, Anna, circa 1930-1965 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Evergood, Philip, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Everhart Museum, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Feigl, Hugo, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Feininger, Lyonel, 1958-1960 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Fink, Sheldon, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Gatch, Lee, 1946-1951 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Geldzahler, Henry, circa 1930-1965 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Graham, John, 1929-1931 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Gromaire, M., 1945-1949 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Grossman, Edwin Booth, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Grosz, George, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Guggenheim, Peggy, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Hamerman, Esther, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Harris, Joseph J., 1953 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Harris, Sidney E., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Hart, Pop, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Hartl, Leon, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Hartley, Marsden, circa 1930-1965 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Hayter, S. W., 1943 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Heckel, Wilhelm, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Holty, Carl, 1939-1960 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Hondius, Gerrit, 1926-1932 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Houmere, Walter, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Howland, Isabella, 1926-1936 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Indiana, Robert, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Johnson, Ray, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Julien Levy Gallery, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Kandinsky, Wassily, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Karfiol, Bernard, 1925-1928 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Kelly, Ellsworth, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Kennedy, Jacqueline, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Kerkham, Earl, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Knaths, Karl, 1940-1955 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Kopman, Benjamin, 1929-1967 (Box 3, Folder 111-112)
    Correspondence, financial records, list.
  - Kopman, Benjamin, 1929-1967 (Box 3, Folder 113-115)
  - Kopman, Benjamin, 1929-1967 (Box 3, Folder 116-118)
    Exhibition announcements and catalogs.
  - Kopman, Benjamin, 1929-1967 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    Photograph.
  - Kubin, Alfred, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - Kuhn, Walt, 1926-1946 (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - Kuniyoshi, Yasuo, 1927-1934 (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - Lehmbruck, Manfred, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - Levinson, A. F., 1926-1936 (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - Lipchitz, Jacques, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - Litwak, Israel, 1945-1953 (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - Loewe, Frederick (composer), 1962 (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - Matisse, Pierre, 1925-1947 (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - Meigs, Margaret, 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Mommer, Paul, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - Museum of Modern Art, New York, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - Neuberger, Roy, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Neumann, J. B., 1929-1960 (Box 4, Folder 2-4)
  - Neumann, Peter, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Nierendorf, Karl, 1925-1958 (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
  - Odets, Clifford (playwright), 1946-1953 (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
  - Orosco, J. C., 1945 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Porter, David, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Pereira, Irene Rice, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Perper, Marc, 1927-1935 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Reder, B., 1960 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Robertson, Mr. (brother of Grandma Moses), 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Robinson, Boardman, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Rockefeller, Mrs. John D., 1930 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Rueckmien, V., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Ryan, Anne, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Salmon, Walter J., 1926-1927 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Schang, F. C., 1951 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Seligman, Jacques, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Seligmann, Kurt, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Shahn, Ben, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Shaw, Artie (musician), 1952 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Sheeler, Charles, 1925-1936 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Shields, Robert, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Simpson, Mert, circa 1930-1965 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Soyer, Moses, 1926-1936 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Sterne, Maurice, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Stieglitz, Alfred, 1924-1936 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Thompson, G. D., 1944-1952 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Truman, Harry S., 1960 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Tryggvadottir, Nina, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Tucker, Richard and Sara, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Urban, Albert, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Valentin, Curt, 1929-1954 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Varda, Jean, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Vye, George, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Weber, Max, 1924-1936 (Box 4, Folder 40-41)
  - Wells, James L., 1931 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - White House, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Whitney, Elisabeth B., 1935 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Willard, Marian (Gallery), 1939-1942 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Wittenberg, Ruth, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Wollheim, G., 1947 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Eva Lee Gallery Consignment and Sales Artist Files, 1960-1972; Series 4
  This series primarily contains photographs of artwork and notes concerning the consignment and sale of specific artwork. Also included are scattered letters, receipts, and printed material. There is a significant amount of materials for Ben Benn, Alexander Calder, Lovis Corinth, Salvadore Dali, Lyonel Feininger, George Grosz, Marsden Hartley, John Hopkins, Rene Magritte, and John Marin.
  Materials are arranged alphabetically by art genre and surname of the artist.
  - Americana, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 48-49)
  - American Portraits, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Arp, Jean, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Aronson, David, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Baylinson, A. S., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Benn, Ben, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 54-57)
  - Benton, Thomas Hart, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Berman, Eugene, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Bombois, Camille, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Buffet, Bernard, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Caffe, Nino, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Calder, Alexander, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 63-65)
  - Chagall, Marc, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Corinth, Lovis, 1963-1968 (Box 4, Folder 67-68)
  - Cowles, Fleur, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Dali, Salvadore, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 70-73)
  - Dufy, Jean, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Ernst, Max, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Feininger, Lyonel, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 76-77)
  - Grosz, George, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 78-80)
  - Guillaumin, Jean B. A., circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Hartley, Marsden, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 82-86)
  - Hartley, Marsden, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 87-91)
  - Hartley, Marsden, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 92-97)
  - Hofer, Carl, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 98)
  - Hopkins, John, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 99-104)
  - Howland, Isabella, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - Laurencin, Marie, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - Lawrence, Jacob, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - Lebduska, Lawrence, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - Magritte, Rene, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 109-110)
  - Maillol, Aristide, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - Marin, John, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 112-113)
  - Marini, Marino, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - Matisse, Henri, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - Matta, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - Mommer, Paul, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - Picasso, Pablo, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 118-119)
  - Religious Spanish Painting, 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 120)
  - Seligmann, Kurt, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 121-122)
  - Shahn, Ben, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 123-126)
  - Shahn, Ben, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 127-130)
  - Simpton, Mert, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 131-132)
  - Soyer, Moses, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 133)
  - Soyer, Raphael, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 134-135)
  - Summers, Carol, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - Tanguy, Yves, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - Tanning, Dorothea, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 138)
  - Vasarely, Victor, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 139)
- Photocopy of Korvettes Art Galleries Auction Catalog, 1970; Series 5
  The catalog records artists' names, titles, and media of their artwork sold at the public auction liquidating the holdings of the Korvettes Art Galleries in Douglaston, New York.
  - Photocopy of Korvettes Art Galleries Auction Catalog and Clipping, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 140)